Guide to the Richard Pommer Papers MC 125
New York University Archives
- Series I: Papers
  - Princeton - Van Zanten, David. "The 'Princeton System' and the Founding of the School Architecture," "Princeton's Beaux Arts and Its New Academicism: From Labatut to the Program of Geddes", undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - "Piranese et Les Francais," Academie de France a Rome, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Perret, notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Students, photos, correspondence, 1988-1992 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Art 370, notes, syllabi, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Place and Dutch symposium - LeFaivre, Liane. "Dirty Realism in European Architecture Today: Making the Stone Stony." Design Book Review. Winter Le Faivre, Liane. "Eros, Architecture, and the Hypnerotomachia Polophili." Design Book Review, Spring, 1990 Pommer, Richard. "On the Corbusian Road." Delft University, Symposium on Context and Modernity, June 12 - 15, 1990. LeFaivre, Liane and Tzonis, Alexander. "The graid and the pathway. An introduction to the work of Dimitris and Susana Antonakakis. With prolegomena to a history of the culture of modern Greek architecture." Architecture in Greece, 15/1981. LeFaivre, Liane and Tzonis, Alexander. "Critical Regionalism: Making the Region Strange." 1990. Heidegger, Martin. "An Ontological Consideration of 'Place,'" Question of Being New York: Twayne, 1958., 1958-1990 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Post-Modernism Bruegmann, Robert. "Architecture Essay for Post-Modernism Book," 1983. Langdon, Philip. "A Good Place to Live." Atlantic Monthly, March 1988., 1983, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Olmstead - Notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - U.S. Post-Modernism Anderson, Perry. "Modernity and Revolution." New Left Review, 1984 Jameson. "Postmodernism, or The Cultural Logic of Late Capitalism." New Left Review, 1984, p. 53 - 92. Hutcheson, Linda. "The Politics of Postmodernism: Parody and History." Foster, Hal. "(Post)Modern Polemics", 1984, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Delft University - "Meier, Corbusier and the 'Sense of Place'" - Symposium on Context and Modernity, Delft University, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Rossi - notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Russia - notes, excerpts from texts, undated (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Place - Geo - Matore, Georges. "L'Espace Humain" (excerpt) Matore, Georges. "Existential Space." Spring 1966. Cox, Harry. "The Restoration of a Sense of Place: A Theological Reflection on the Visual Environment." 1968. Briggs, Asa. "The Sense of Place." 1967. Webber, Melvin M. "The Urban Place and the Workplace Urban realm." 1964. Webber, Melvin M. "Order in Diversity: Community without Propinquity." 1963., 1963-1968 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Richardson - Newman, M.W. "Granite Hunt." 1972. Sprague, Paul E. "John Jacob Glessner and His House on Prairie Avenue, Chicago." Glessner, John. "The Story of a House." 1923., 1923, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Sant'Elia - Orto, Luisa. "The Stile Liberty and the Origins of Sant'Elia." 1990. Marinetti, F.T. "The Founding and the Manifesto of Futurism 1909." (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Semper - Rykwert, Joseph. "Gottfried Semper and the Problem of Style." Semper, Gottfried. "On the Origin of Some Architectural Styles." 1853. Semper, Gottfried. "The Development of the Wall and Wall Construction in Antiquity." 1853 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Stirling - notes, excerpt, undated (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Shinohara - Shinohara, Kazuo. "Abstracts with a Nationality." 1979. Shinohara, Kazuo. "Architectual Theory for 16 houses." 1971 Shinahara, Kazuo. "Preparations for New Functional Space.", 1971-1979 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Skidmore, Owings and Merrill - News from Lever House and Fact Sheet, undated (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Smithson - Wright, Laurie Susan. "The Smithsons' Early Designs as an Exemplification of Post-War British Architecture." 1985 Cook, Peter. "Regarding the Smthsons." Architectural Review, Nov. 1972 - Bibliography, 1985, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Saarinen/Roche - "Unique Architectural Elements at the General Motors Technical Center." General Motors Engineering Journal, Vol 3, No. 3, May/June, 1956. - Notes and bibliography (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Skyscraper - Bletter, Rosemarie Haag. "The Invention of Skyscraper: Notes on its Diverse Histories." Assemblage, Feb. 1987. - Bibliography, notes (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Schinkel - Adler, Friedrich. "Die Bauschule zu Berlin von C.F. Schinkel." 1981. Zuchold, H. Gerd. "Bemerkungen zu Schinkels verhaltnis zur Kunst der Antike." 1982 Behr, Adalbert. "Griechenlands Blute" und die "Fortsetzung der Geshichte." Kunsttheorie Karl Friedrich Schinkels, 1984. "Collection of Architectural Designs - An English Translation of Schinkel's Descriptive Commentary." Peschken, Goerd. "Technologische Asthetik in Schinkel's Architektur." 1988. Stahl, Fritz. Karl Friedrich Schinkel (excerpt) Schinkel, Karl. "Architektur Malerei Kunstgewerbe." Crimp, Douglas. "Origin of the Museum." Art Journal, Winter 1987., 1981-1988 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Steiner - notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Soane - notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Adler and Sullivan's Auditorium Theater - Geraniotis, Roula. "The Auditorium Theater: An Example of German Design Influence in Chicago." 1985 - Correspondence with Geraniotis, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Shapiro - Shapiro, Meyer. "The Social Bases of Art." 1986. (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Soleri - Soleri, Paulo. "Envisioned Cities of the 21st Century." 1979-80. - Notes, 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - De Stijl - van Doesburg, Theo. "Toward a Plastic (Beeldende) Architecture." De Stijl Journal, 1918-22, excerpts. "De Invoed van de Stijlbeweging in Duitschland." 1923. (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - Spare Time - notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - Speer - Lanz, Barbara Miller. "Interpreting Nazi Architecture: the Case of Albert Speer." College Art Association, 2/16/89 Larsson, Von Lars Olaf. "Klassizimus in der Architektur des 20 Jahrhunderts." Larrson. "Classicism in the Architecture of the XXth Century." 1985. Krier, Leon. "An Architecture of Desire.", 1978 (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Skyscraper Genre - Paulsen, Friedrich. "Hochhäuser Für Deutschland." 1922 "Grundfëssliches zur Hochhausfrage." Die Bauwelt, 1922. (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Team 10, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - Terragni - Schumacher, Thomas L. "From Abstraction to Symbolism and Back Again: Terragni's Danteum and the Dilemma of Architectural Autonomy." Harvard Architecture Review, 1984. (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - Tessenow - Carter, Huntley. "The New Spirit in Dresden." The New Spirit in Drama and Art. New York: Mitchell Kennerley, 1913. De Michelis, Marco. "Modernity and Reform, Heinrich Tessenow and the Institut Dalcroze at Hellerau." Yale Architecture Journal, perspecta 26. - assorted excerpts (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Tschumi, Bernard. "Park de la Villette, Paris." 1988 (Box 10, Folder 58)
  - Taut - Taut, Heinrich. "Bruno taut - mein Vater und Freund." Architektur de DDR, 1980. - assorted excerpts and notes re: Taut (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - U.S., '50s and '60s - Johanson, Welse, Bellensch - notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - U.S., '50s - notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - American Modern - notes, outline for book on American architecture, undated (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - Architecture ca. 1960 - notes (Box 10, Folder 63)
  - U.S. '20s - notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 64)
  - American Architectural Education - Geraniotis, Roala. "The University of Illinois and German Architectural Education." Journal of Architectural Education, Summer, 1985. (Box 10, Folder 65)
  - U.S. '40s and '50s - Scully, Vincent J. "Doldrums in the Suburbs." Journal of the Society of Architectural Historians, 1965. Group discussion of United Nations buildings - Architectural Forum, Nov. 1950, 1950, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 66)
  - American 19th-Century Houses - notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 67)
  - American 19th-Century Miscellaneous - notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 68)
  - American '30s - Gutheim, Frederick. "Roland Wank 1890 - 1970." Architectural Forum, December, 1970. Otto, Christian F. "International Style in the United States." Otto. "American Skyscraper and Weimar Modern: Transactions between Fact and Idea." Jordy, William F. "The Aftermath of the Bauhaus in America: Gropius, Mies, and Breuer." (Box 10, Folder 69)
  - Art 370 - Frank Lloyd Wright, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058546 8
  - Frank Lloyd Wright - bibliographies, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Frank Lloyd Wright - Francisco Terrace Apartments, photos, blueprints, correspondence, 1965-1973 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Airports, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Alexander, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Der Platz der Republik/Berlin, 1917-1930 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Werner, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Berlin C P, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Berlin, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Berlin, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Berlin, writers, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Berliner Siedlungen, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Berlin, undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Brooklyn Museum, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Bay Area Architecture, 1949, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Van Eyck, 1960-1975 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Van Doesburg, undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - American Colonial and English Vernacular Architecture, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Viollet-Le-Duc, undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Ven de Velde, undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Venturi, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Vinciarelli, undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Venturi, 1965-1984 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Wagner, undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Weinbrenner, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Werkbund Arbeit Zukunft, undated (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Women, undated (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - World War II, undated (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Broadacre City, undated (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Early Frank Lloyd Wright, undated (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Art 370, Frank Lloyd Wright, undated (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Late Frank Lloyd Wright, undated (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - City Plan Bibliography, undated (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - City Planning, undated (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Baumeister, 1876-1911 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Brinckmann, undated (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Linear, undated (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Fritsch, undated (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - City Plan, undated (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Endell, undated (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Comey, undated (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Modern City Planning, 1967-1987 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Collins, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - California, undated (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - Chicago, undated (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Columbia/Reston, undated (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - Environment Cities, undated (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - Housing - England, 1931-, 1971-1974 (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - Forest Hills Gardens, 1916-1975 (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - Frankfurt, undated (Box 11, Folder 50)
  - Frankfurt, undated (Box 11, Folder 51)
  - May, undated (Box 11, Folder 52)
  - May, undated (Box 11, Folder 53)
  - France City Planning, 1915-1919, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 54)
  - Invention de Carouge, 1772-1792, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 55)
  - Gardens/City Parks, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058547 6
  - German Housing, 1895-1971 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - German Site Plan, 1907-1987 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Art 370, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Haussmann, 1927 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Ebenezer Howard, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - European Housing, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Hegemann, 1927-1990 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Image of City, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Jackson, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Los Angeles, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Hotels/Motels, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Mobile Homes, 1955-1979 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Mumford, 1989-1990 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1984-1989 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Italian Museum Design - J. Perry, undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Graves/Newark, 1978-1981 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - I.M. Pei/Museums, 1979-1990 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Renzo Piano and the Menil Collection, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Arata Isozaki, 1976-1990 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Charles Moore and the Williams College of Art, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Museums, 1955-1988 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Newport, undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - New Towns, undated (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Plunz, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Art 370a Modern City Planning and New York City - Bibliographies, undated (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Grand Central, undated (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Rockefeller Center, undated (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - American City Planning, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Art 370a, Modern City Planning and New York City, Fall, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - New York City Zoning, 1976-1985 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Art 370, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Art 370, undated (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Regional Planning, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Co-op City, undated (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - New York City Low-Rise Housing, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Battery Park City, 1979-1989 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - SAH - New York City Architecture and Design Between the Wars Conference, undated (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Art 370, undated (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Bender, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Committee for the Preservation of Architectural Records, 1977-1980 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Committee for the Preservation of Architectural Records, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Previ/Lima, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Roadside Arch, 1955-1971 (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - Gomley, undated (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - Acorn Houses, undated (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - Rome, 19th and 20th centuries, undated (Box 12, Folder 47)
  - Art 370 - Roadside Architecture Seminar, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 48)
  - Camillo Sitte, 1927 (Box 12, Folder 49)
  - Unwin, 1909, 1979-1982 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058548 4
  - Vienna, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Martin Wagner, 1918-1925 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Vernacular, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Martin Wagner II, 1915-1979 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Cities, 1966, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Washington D.C., 1991 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Zellenbau, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Lane, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Q file, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Banham, 1955-1981 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Colquhoun, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Giedion, 1928 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Giedion II, 1944-1981 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Hudnut, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Meyer, Peter, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Pevsner Pioneers, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Rowe, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Debord - Spectacle, undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Troubled Times, undated (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Persico, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Gustav Platz, undated (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Theory: Criticism and Bibliography, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Sociology - Environmental Psychology - Terminology, 1967-1971 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Systems, Buildings, Prefabs, undated (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Scul, undated (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Symposium on the Politicizing of the Arts in the Western World, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Pleasure Palaces, etc., undated (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Theaters/Art Centers, undated (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Perspecta, undated (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Criticism 1920s, undated (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Functionalism, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous Parts, undated (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Flat Roof I, undated (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Flat Roof II, undated (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Flat Roof - Pommer paper/presentation, undated (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Flat Roof Text/Presentation, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Shand, 1934-1935 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Taut, 1929 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Projects, undated (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Technology Structures, undated (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Van Zanten, David, 1989-1990 (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - American Architecture and the German Connection Symposium, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - American Architecture and the German Connection conference, 1987-1989 (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - American Architecture and the German Connection conference, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 46)
  - Columbia University Seminar on the City, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 47)
  - Sander, August, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 48)
  - Muthesius, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 49)
  - Loewy, undated (Box 13, Folder 50)
  - Chicago Address, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058549 2
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Mies and Political Ideology Article, 1922-1986 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Mies Politics, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Mies photocopies, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Van Der Rohe - archival collections, 1981-1985 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Mies Van Der Rohe Manuscripts, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Van Der Rohe - Books, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Van Der Rohe - correspondence, 1929, 1984-1987 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Van Der Rohe seminar, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Mies, photocopies, 1929-1969 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Mies - Miscellaneous bibliography, undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Mies - miscellaneous, undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Riehl, undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Luxembourg, undated (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Alexanderplatz, 1929, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Berlin Building Expo, 1931 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Tuhendhat, 1931-1932 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Neue Wache, undated (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Afrikanische, undated (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Oral Histories - Mies and Blake, undated (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Ruegenberg, undated (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Brussels, photocopies, undated (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Brussels Exhibition 1935, 1934-35, 1985-86, undated (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Deutsche Volk-Deutsche Arbeit, 1934 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - "G" Group, undated (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Mies - Nazis, 1933-1985 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Nazi Archives, undated (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Berlin Document Center, 1933-1938, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Reichsbank I, 1933, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Reichsbank II, 1933-1937 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - American Mies, 1953-1986 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Mies - followers, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - American Mies - MOMA Architecture, 1934- (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Architectural Forum, undated (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Illinois Institute of Technology, undated (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - Mies in America - text, undated (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - Seagram building, undated (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Mies and Modern Classicism - article, 1991-1992 (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Articles on Mies, 1984-1990 (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - Barcelona Pavilion, undated (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - Classicism-General, undated (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - Mies and Modern Classicism, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - American Academy of Pediatrics, undated (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - German Classicism, 1908-1972 (Box 14, Folder 45)
  - Westheim, 1913-1932 (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - Kant, 1912-1991 (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - Wölfflin, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 48)
  - Mies - Germany, 1910-1988 (Box 14, Folder 49)
  - Neumeyer, 1979-1990 (Box 14, Folder 50)
  - Mies and Modern Classicism Lecture - Graham Foundation, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 51)
  - Mies/Classicism, 1955-1990 (Box 14, Folder 52)
  - Mies and Modern Classicism Lecture, undated (Box 14, Folder 53)
  - Veneria: Italian Architectural Publications, 1917-1970 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058550 0
  - Piedmont - Miscellaneous Publications, 1926-1969 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Torino - Miscellaneous Publications, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Architecture 1750-1875, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Architecture 1750-1875, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Architecture 1750-1875, Fall 1990, bibliography (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Architecture 1887-1914, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Architecture 1887-1914, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Architecture 1887-1914, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - History 1890-1914, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Architecture since 1945, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Architecture since 1945, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Architecture since 1945, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Architecture circa 1900, undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Architecture 1914-1945, undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Moore and Bay Region style architecture, seminar 1988, Venturi, Kaha, undated (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Architecture 1900 to the Present: Problems in Historiography, seminar, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Architecture 1900 to the Present: Problems in Historigraphy, seminar, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Le Corbusier Seminar, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Le Corbusier Seminar, Spring 1990, 1875-1909, 1990, 1895-1909 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Twentieth Century Architecture: Museum Design Seminar, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Twentieth Century Architecture: Museum Design Seminar, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Museum Design Seminar: Historiography, 1967-1990, undated (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Museum Design Seminar: Historiography, 1951-1987, undated (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Museum Seminar bibliography, undated (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Architectural Theory, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058551 8
  - Frampton, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Architectural Criticism since 1945 seminar, Spring 1991 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Architectural Criticism - Mumford, 1932-1963, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Vidler resumé, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Seminar Spring 1992, rejected, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Art 272, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Art 272, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Art 273 - 20th-Century Architecture, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Art 273 - 20th-Century Architecture, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Art 370 - Corbusier Seminar, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Art 370 - Corbusier Seminar, 1975, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Art 370 - Corbusier Seminar, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - "Recent Architecture and Mother Nature" - speech, undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - "Nature in Architecture" speech at CAA, undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Art 370 - Architecture and Nature in the Industrial Revolution, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Art 170 - Modern Architecture, Summer, 1970-1971 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Columbia, Mies, undated (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Mies Seminar, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Mies Seminar, MIT, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Transcripts, early resumés, 1948-1963 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Projects, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Complimentary letters, 1976-1988 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Class Record Books, 1966-1988 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Art 301 - Independent Study, 1979-1986 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Adam Mitchell, 1988-1989 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Bruegmann, 1982-1990 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Dennis Doordan, undated (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Golan, undated (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Totalitarianism, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Totalitarianism, 1984 Mar. (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - History Talk, 1981-1987 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - "History Without Meaning" speech at ASCA Conference, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - SAH Commemoration Speech - "History in the Service of Architecture: Post-Modernism and Reappraisal of the Past", 1936 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - "On the Corbusian Road" Delft University Symposium, undated (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - German Werkbund Conference, April 1980, undated (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - Architecture 1914-1945, syllabus, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058552 6
  - Architecture circa 1900, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Architecture circa 1900, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Architecture 1914-45, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Architecture 1914-45, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Art 370A - Louis Kahn and His Influence, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Architecture since 1945, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Architecture since 1945, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Kahn - Dacca, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Kahn Seminar, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 11)